esko.com 2019-04-29

# 

* * *

This Online Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how Esko-Graphics bvba and its Esko-branded affiliates (“Esko”) handle Personal Data provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by Esko that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “Esko Sites”). Esko is the data controller for the processing of Personal Data under applicable law.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to Esko Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party websites to which the Esko Sites may link.

## Summary

This summary section provides a brief overview of our Privacy Policy. Please read the full Privacy Policy  for more detailed information.

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Your Information
  * Information We Share
  * Your Privacy Choices
  * Security
  * Accessing Our Sites Globally
  * Changes to Our Privacy Policy

### Information We Collect

Esko collects the following types of information through the Esko Sites:

  * **Information you provide.** Personal Data you provide when registering for our products and services, responding to questionnaires or surveys, or contacting Esko customer service.
  * **Information collected automatically.** Your IP address and non-identifying information about your use of Esko Sites may be collected automatically using tracking technologies, such as cookies. Your website browser software can be set to reject all cookies; however, cookies can allow you to take advantage of some of the site’s essential features, which may not work if you reject cookies.
  * **Information collected from other sources.** We may combine information about you from Esko Sites, information collected offline, or from external parties.

### How We Use Your Information

Esko uses the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with the Esko products and services you request.
  * To offer and provide information about similar and/or related products and services.
  * To customize and improve your experience on Esko Sites.
  * To generally improve our products and Esko Sites and other internal business purposes.
  * To notify and report to authorities under our legal obligations.

Under European data protection laws, Esko must have a legal basis to process your Personal Data. The legal basis that applies in a particular instance will depend on the specific purposes described above for which Esko is processing your Personal Data:

  * In certain instances, Esko may ask for your consent to collect and process your Personal Data. Should you choose to provide your consent, you may later withdraw your consent by contacting us as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” section. Please note that the withdrawal of consent will not affect processing which has already occurred.
  * In other instances, the processing of your Personal Data may be necessary in order to comply with an applicable law or regulation or for the performance of a contract to which you are subject. You may not be able to opt out of this processing, or your choice to opt out may impact our ability to perform a contractual obligation otherwise owed to you.
  * In yet other instances, Esko may process your Personal Data based on Esko’s legitimate interests in communicating with you about our products and services, and about scientific research and educational opportunities. You have the right to opt out of all such processing of your Personal Data. You may do so by contacting us as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” section.

Processing operations may include the recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Data. The Personal Data we collect about you may be stored for ten years following the most recent interaction we have had with you, after which point it will be archived only for so long as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out above, in accordance with applicable laws.

### Information We Share

Esko does not sell or disclose your Personal Data to third parties without your consent, except:

  * To affiliates and third-party service providers to provide services and information on our sites, including online marketing and advertising, and to support our business operations. We require these parties to handle Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * To affiliates to offer and provide information about related products and services. We do not share Personal Data from countries that require consent, unless consent has been obtained in advance of sharing with affiliates. We require these parties to handle your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * To our distribution channel partners in connection with the sale and distribution of our products and services. We require these parties to handle your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * To another company in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of Esko’s affiliates.
  * To governing regulatory authorities or as may otherwise be necessary for Esko to comply with a legal obligation or demand.

In the event Esko decides to reorganize or divest our business through sale, merger, or acquisition, Esko may share Personal Data about you with actual or prospective purchasers. We will require any actual or prospective purchasers to treat this Personal Data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

You can find all our [affiliates here](http://www.danaher.com/our-businesses/business-directory)

### Your Privacy Choices

You have the right to see and get a copy of the Personal Data about you that we maintain as well as to ask us to make corrections to inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data about you. You have the right to receive data that you have provided to us in a machine-readable format and to transmit that data to another controller. You may also request the erasure of your Personal Data or the restriction of its processing, or object to the processing of Personal Data about you. To seek access to Personal Data about you, to file a concern, complaint, or request for correction, or to opt out of particular programs, please contact our Privacy Leader by clicking on the “Contact Us” link on the Esko Site you are using, by using the Esko contact information on the Esko mobile application you are using, or by e-mailing us at [privacy@esko.com](mailto:privacy@esko.com). You may also send a letter to the following address:

Esko  
Privacy Leader  
Kortrijksesteenweg 1095  
BE-9051 Gent  
Belgium

Your local Data Protection Authority is responsible for making sure that applicable privacy laws are followed in your locality.  For more information about your privacy rights, or if you are not able to resolve a problem directly with us and wish to make a complaint, please contact your local Data Protection Authority.

### Security

Esko maintains controls to protect and secure Personal Data, but when you share Personal Data online there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could gain access to your information.

### Accessing Our Sites Globally

By using this site, you understand that your Personal Data will be collected, stored, and processed in Belgium and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations. Esko may transmit Personal Data about you to affiliates worldwide. These affiliates may in turn transmit Personal Data about you to other affiliates. Some affiliates may be in countries that do not ensure an adequate level of data protection. Nevertheless, all affiliates are required to treat Personal Data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. To obtain additional information regarding the safeguards we have in place for cross-border transfers of Personal Data, please contact us using the information provided in the “Your Privacy Choices” section.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Check this Privacy Policy regularly, as we may change or update portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time, subject to any applicable consent requirements. Any changes will be promptly posted to this page and accompanied by a new effective date at the top of this page.

* * *

This Online Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how we handle the Personal Data provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by Esko-Graphics bvba, Kortrijksesteenweg 1095, BE-9051 Gent, Belgium, and its Esko-branded affiliates (“Esko”) that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “Esko Sites”). Esko is the data controller for the processing of Personal Data under applicable law.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to Esko Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party websites to which the Esko Sites may link.

## Types of Information We Collect Online

The types of Personal Data that we may collect while you use the Esko Sites are described in this section and include both information that you provide to us and information that we collect automatically when you use the Esko Sites.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Data” means information that identifies you or that could reasonably be used to identify you. Examples of Personal Data include name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.

### Information You Provide

You do not have to register for a service or program to receive much of the information available through the Esko Sites. However, some of our content is available only to registered or identified users and will require you to set up a profile or provide specific information about yourself in order to provide you the content.

**Personal Data You Provide When Visiting Esko Sites**

Esko collects Personal Data that you provide on Esko Sites, for example, when purchasing a product, requesting marketing information, contacting Esko customer service, or responding to Esko questionnaires or surveys. This could include:

  * Contact information such as your name, address, phone number, or e-mail address
  * Registration information such as your username or password
  * Employment, education and other background information when you inquire about employment with Esko
  * Payment information (such as banking information, payment card number, expiration date, delivery address, and billing address)
  * Content you may provide (for example, when you complete our Online Contact Form or submit other information).

**Personal Data You Share During Other Interactions with Esko**

You may contact Esko to ask questions, discuss your concerns, or report issues regarding our products or services. If you communicate with or request information from Esko, you may be prompted to provide your contact information as well as any Personal Data that is relevant to your request.

### Information That May Be Collected Automatically

When you use the Esko Sites, we also may collect certain usage and device information automatically as described below.

**IP Address**

We may record the Internet Protocol ("IP") address of your computer or other electronic device when you visit the Esko Sites. An IP address identifies the electronic device you use to access the Esko Sites, which allows us to maintain communication with your computer as you move about the Esko Sites and to customize content.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

We also collect information about your use of the Esko Sites through tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons. A “cookie” is a unique numeric code that is transferred to your computer to track your interests and preferences and to recognize you as a return visitor. A “web beacon” is a transparent graphic image placed on a website, e-mail or advertisement that enables the monitoring of things such as user activity and site traffic. These technologies help remember your preferences and allow us to bring you the content and features that are likely to be of greatest interest to you on the basis of “clickstream” data that shows your previous activities on the Esko Sites.

We utilize Google Display Advertising (such as Display Advertising on Facebook and Instagram, Retargeting with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting) to (1) show you our ads on other websites based on your prior visits to the Esko Sites, and (2) better understand our ad impressions and use of ad services. In connection with the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting service, we may use data from Google's interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics to understand and improve our marketing campaigns and site content.

Some of our online advertising takes place through Google Display Advertising. As part of this program, we use Google Analytics features such as Retargeting. In connection with that feature and others offered by ad networks, we and the operators of ad networks, including Google, may use third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) – and in some cases first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) – to inform, optimize and serve ads across the internet, based on a user's past visits to the Esko Sites. We may also show you ads from some of our affiliates when you visit the Esko Sites.

You can opt out of Google Ads by visiting [Google Ad Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences). If you do not want your data used by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at the [Google Analytics opt-out page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

This Esko Site is not designed to respond to "do not track" signals received from browsers.

To learn more about cookies and other tracking technologies, including how to disable them, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). Please note that some cookies are essential to the functioning of our sites and deleting or disabling them will reduce the site’s functionality.

**Mobile Tracking**

Some Esko Sites are available either as mobile applications or mobile sites that you can use on your mobile device. If you use a mobile device to access and use the Esko Sites, we may collect the following mobile-specific information in addition to the other information described above: device or advertising ID, device type, hardware type, media access control (“MAC”) address, international mobile equipment identity (“IMEI”), the version of your mobile operating system, the platform used to access or download the Esko Site (e.g., Apple, Google, Amazon, Windows), location information and usage information about your device and your use of the Esko Sites.

### Information Collected from Other Sources

We may combine information about you from a visit to one Esko Site with information about you from visits to other Esko Sites. We may also combine information about you that is collected through the Esko Sites with information that we have collected offline, as well as with information provided to us by third parties, such as third-party list providers.

## How We Use Your Information

We use your Personal Data to provide you the products and services you request, communicate with you, improve your experience on the Esko Sites, generally improve our products and services, and for other internal business purposes. These uses may also include the recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Data. The Personal Data we collect about you may be stored for ten years following the most recent interaction we have had with you, after which point it will be archived only for so long as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out above, in accordance with applicable laws.

**Providing Products and Services You Request**

If you choose to purchase our products or receive our services, we use the Personal Data that you provide through the Esko Sites to manage your orders and invoices, to process payments, to respond to your questions, to provide you the products or services you request, and to offer an optimal customer experience.

**Marketing**

You may also receive marketing information from Esko and our affiliates, such as offers regarding similar or related products or services, invitations to participate in surveys about our products, or notifications about special promotions. In such cases, we will use your contact and other Personal Data to send you marketing information.

**Customized User Experiences**

The Personal Data that you provide may be used to create customized offers, information, or services tailored to your interests and preferences. Also, we may use your IP address and the data that we obtain automatically through the use of cookies or similar tracking technologies to make our Esko Sites easier to use and navigate as well as to personalize the content provided on the Esko Sites by anticipating the information and services that may be of interest to you.

**Business and Product Improvement**

In order to discover new facts that could help Esko better understand customer needs and help improve, develop, and evaluate products, services, materials, and programs, Esko analyzes the information that you have provided. For these purposes, Esko does not use information that can directly identify you.

**Site Analytics and Improvement**

We may use the information that you provide and the information we collect automatically about your use of the Esko Sites to monitor user traffic patterns and preferences for site improvement, analytics, and optimization.

**Bug Reports and Performance Data**

Esko collects data on the performance of our products, services and website, and on features used. Based on such data, Esko is able to diagnose problems that occur when using our products, services or website. In addition, such data is useful for improving our products, services, website and for offering future solutions. Depending on the type of product or service and its settings, such data may include anonymous measurement data or may be processed in combination with your Esko ID, IP address, or access credentials used in combination with our products and services.  Error‐reports generated may further contain specific data such as the type or severity of the problem and details of the software or hardware that is involved.

**Support Data**

When you request Esko’s support for troubleshooting errors or problems associated with your use of our products or services, Esko collects information about you and about your hardware, software, and other details that are relevant to the support incident. This concerns data such as but not limited to contact or authentication information, information on the status of the device and the application at the time of the error and during the diagnosis, the content of files at the time of occurrence of an error and data on other software on your device, as well as system and registry data software installations and hardware configurations.

**License Management Routines**

The services that Esko provide (Software As A Service) and the software that Esko licenses, include technical means necessary to allow you to use certain functionalities, or to limit your use of these products to the functionalities that you licensed. As part of such mechanisms, certain data is collected and stored either locally (as part of local license management) or sent to Esko for remote processing, such as user name and password (e.g. the access credentials you use in combination with software provided in a Software‐As‐A-Service model, your Esko ID, computer name, platform, activation account, machine serial, IP address, and other data of a similar nature).

**Forward to a Friend Feature**

If our referral service is available and you choose to use it to tell a friend about an Esko Site, we will ask you for your friend's name and e-mail address. Your e-mail address will appear as the sender of the e-mail and we will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the Esko Site. Both your e-mail address and the recipient's e-mail address will not be used for any other purpose except to facilitate the sending of this one-time e-mail to your friend. Esko stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail and tracking the success of our referral service.

**Legal Basis for Processing**

Under European data protection laws, Esko must have a legal basis to process your Personal Data. The legal basis that applies in a particular instance will depend on the specific purposes described above for which Esko is processing your Personal Data:

  * In certain instances, Esko may ask for your consent to collect and process your Personal Data. Should you choose to provide your consent, you may later withdraw your consent by contacting us as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” section.  Please note that the withdrawal of consent will not affect processing which has already occurred.
  * In other instances, the processing of your Personal Data may be necessary in order to comply with an applicable law or regulation or for the performance of a contract to which you are subject. You may not be able to opt out of this processing, or your choice to opt out may impact our ability to perform a contractual obligation otherwise owed to you.
  * In yet other instances, Esko may process your Personal Data based on Esko’s legitimate interests in communicating with you about our products and services, and about scientific research and educational opportunities.  You have the right to opt out of all such processing of your Personal Data.  You may do so by contacting us as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” section.

## Information We Share

We only share your Personal Data with third parties as described below. We do not sell or disclose Personal Data to third parties for their own marketing purposes.

**Third-Party Advertising and Online Behavioral Advertising**

You may be provided with online advertisements of Esko products and services on third-party websites and mobile services that are tailored to you, for example, on the basis of information that you provide to Esko or a third-party website you are visiting, or your browsing activity, purchases, or interests. These types of tailored online advertisements may come through several sources, such as the following:

  * We may share with our advertising service providers your non-identifying information that we have obtained from cookies and other tracking technologies on our Esko Sites.
  * Some Esko Sites may participate in online behavioral advertising (this is also sometimes called re-target advertising or interest-based advertising). You can identify these sites by the “AdChoices” icon in the advertisement. Our advertising network partners may place and use cookies on Esko Sites and on other third-party websites to collect information about your activities in order to provide you with online advertisements that are based on your interests. When an Esko online behavioral advertisement is delivered to you, you will see an “AdChoices” icon. Clicking on the icon or link will take you to a website where you can manage or opt out of the use of data about your browsing history that is used for the delivery of online behavioral advertisements. If you opt out, you may still see advertisements online, including advertisements from Esko that are based on other information (e.g., based on the content of the page being viewed rather than your prior clickstream activity). In some cases, data may still be collected about your browsing activity by these third-party advertisers, but they will not use this data to deliver advertisements that are based on your past online browsing behavior. You can also opt out now by visiting [http://youradchoices.com](http://youradchoices.com/).
  * Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to websites with which the browser communicates. As of the Effective Date of this Privacy Policy, an industry standard has not yet been established on how to respond to these signals. Therefore, Esko does not currently respond to these signals. As discussed above, you can opt out from advertisers that use your browsing history to deliver online behavioral advertisements by visiting [http://youradchoices.com](http://youradchoices.com/).

**Affiliates, Distribution Channel Partners, Vendors, and Suppliers**

We have relationships with affiliates, distribution channel partners, vendors, and suppliers, who help us operate our business and for whom it may be necessary to have access to your Personal Data in the course of providing services to Esko or in connection with the sale and distribution of our products and services. We will not authorize these parties to use your Personal Data for any purpose that is not related to the business operations of Esko or its affiliates, and we do not share Personal Data from countries that require consent, unless appropriate consent has been obtained in advance of sharing with affiliates. We require them to handle your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Co-Branded Sites**

We may partner with other companies to provide you with content or services on a joint or “co-branded” basis. At a co branded site, you will see both the Esko logo and the logo of the co-branding partner displayed on your screen. You should read the individual privacy policies of our co-branding partners, as they may differ in some respects from ours. Reading these policies will help you to make an informed decision about whether to provide your information to a given site.

**Product Reports**

If you contact Esko regarding your experience in using one of our products, we may use the information that you provide in submitting reports to the applicable government regulatory authority, as required of us by law.

**Legal Rights and Obligations**

In certain limited circumstances, Esko may need to disclose your Personal Data in order to comply with a legal obligation or demand, such as to comply with reporting obligations to applicable governing regulatory authorities regarding the safety of our products, or in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of the Esko’s affiliates. In such instances, we will take measures to protect your Personal Data to the extent possible. We also reserve the right to use Personal Data to investigate and prosecute users who violate our rules or who engage in behavior that is illegal or harmful to others or to others’ property.

**Change in Organization**

In the event Esko decides to reorganize or divest our business through sale, merger, or acquisition, Esko may share Personal Data about you with actual or prospective purchasers.  We will require any actual or prospective purchasers to treat this Personal Data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

## Children Privacy

Esko does not knowingly collect or use any Personal Data directly from children on Esko Sites (Esko defines “children” as minors younger than 18). We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, to communicate with us, or to use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

## Your Privacy Choices

You have the right to see and get a copy of the Personal Data about you that we maintain as well as to ask us to make corrections to inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data about you.  You may have the right to receive data that you have provided to us in a machine-readable format and to transmit that data to another controller. You may also request the erasure of your Personal Data or the restriction of its processing, or object to the processing of Personal Data about you. To seek access to Personal Data about you, to file a concern, complaint, or request for correction, or to opt out of particular programs, please contact our Privacy Leader by clicking on the “Contact Us” link on the Esko Site you are using, by using the Esko contact information on the Esko mobile application you are using, or by e-mailing us at [privacy@esko.com](mailto:privacy@esko.com). You may also send a letter to the following address:

Esko  
Privacy Leader  
Kortrijksesteenweg 1095  
BE-9051 Gent  
Belgium

Your local Data Protection Authority is responsible for making sure that applicable privacy laws are followed in your locality.  For more information about your privacy rights, or if you are not able to resolve a problem directly with us and wish to make a compliant, please contact your local Data Protection Authority.

In all communications to Esko, please include your e-mail address, the website address, mobile application, and/or specific Esko product to which you provided your Personal Data (e.g., esko.com), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete, amend, or correct your Personal Data and are contacting us by e-mail, please put “Deletion Request” or “Amendment/Correction Request” in the subject line of the e-mail. We will respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner and may need to further confirm your identity in order to process certain requests.

## Data Security

Esko maintains reasonable technical, administrative, and physical controls to secure any Personal Data collected through the Esko Sites. However, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could intercept an internet transmission, or that someone will find a way to thwart our security systems. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting Personal Data over the internet, especially your financial information. Esko cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your Personal Data; therefore, when submitting Personal Data to Esko Sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks

## Third-Party Sites and Social Media Plug-ins

This Privacy Policy does not apply to Esko Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy, or to third-party websites to which the Esko Sites may link. The Esko Sites may use social media plug-ins (e.g., the Facebook “Like” button, “Share to Twitter” button) to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit Esko Sites, the operator of the social plug-in can place a cookie on your computer or other electronic device that enables that operator to recognize individuals who have previously visited our site. If you are logged into the social media website (e.g., Facebook, Twitter) while browsing on our Esko Site, the social media plug-in allows that social media website to receive information about your visit to our Esko Site. The social media plug-in also allows the social media website to share information about your activities on our Esko Site with other users of their social media website. These sharing settings are managed by the social media website and governed by its privacy policy.

## Accessing Our Sites Globally

This site is owned and operated by Esko in Belgium, but the information you provide will be accessible to our affiliates, vendors, and suppliers in other countries in accordance with this policy. Furthermore, if you are visiting this site from a country other than Belgium, your communications with us will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international borders. The level of legal protection for Personal Data is not the same in all countries; however, we will take the security measures described in this Privacy Policy in an effort to keep your information secure. By using this site, you understand that your Personal Data will be stored and processed in Belgium and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations.

### Notice to California Residents

Subject to certain limitations under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents may ask us to provide them with (i) a list of certain categories of Personal Data that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (ii) the identity of those third parties. To make this request, California residents may contact us at [privacy@esko.com](mailto:privacy@esko.com).

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We will only use your Personal Data in the manner described in the Privacy Policy that is in effect at the time that the information was collected from you or as authorized by you. However, and subject to any applicable consent requirements, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page with a new effective date. Esko encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Any Personal Data collected upon your continued use of the Esko Sites will be handled in accordance with the newly effective Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 25 2018.
